## Egor Philippov FULL STACK ENGINEER

W: egorphilippov.me
G: github.com/lone-cloud
E: egor@nidratech.com

### **ABOUT**

I am an accomplished and passionate technology professional. A highly adaptable, innovative and articulate communicator, I pride myself in my flexibility to work on all parts of an application, be it on the server, browser or mobile.

I specialize in building world class, headless, ecommerce web applications. I am well familiar and comfortable working with Shopify, Recurly and AuthO platforms.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **PANASONIC**

### SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER

Remote Apr 2020 - Present

- Systems design, full stack development and dev-ops for an upcoming ecommerce web application.
- Full stack development using Next.js (TypeScript) of a new ecommerce web application. Backend development of gRPC microservices using Micronaut (Kotlin).
- Establishing and enforcing best software development practices, purchase flow (headless Shopify, Recurly) with PCI compliance, CI/CD implementation, email templating and general build + deployment automation.
- Wrote an open source library (<u>next-deploy</u>) for Next.js to aid with GitHub and serverless deployments to AWS.

#### GOOGLE

### **FULL STACK ENGINEER**

Remote & Palo Alto, US Oct 2016 - Apr 2020  Full stack development of various various enterprise applications for Google Store and Nest including enterprise.nest.com, <u>hvac.nest.com</u> and <u>home.nest.com/login</u>

### NIDRATECH LTD

### **TECHNICAL LEAD**

Vancouver, Canada Aug 2015 - Present

Lead the development of several web, mobile and browser applications:

- tomati.io A mobile app for searching and ranking
   Canadian restaurants based on health inspection reports.
- <u>huegasm.com</u> A browser extension, web and mobile app for controlling Philips Hue lights and synchronizing them with the beat of your music.

# ABSOLUTE SOFTWARE

Vancouver, Canada Jan 2014 - Oct 2016

# OPENBET TECHNOLOGIES

Burnaby, Canada Aug 2012 - Jan 2014

### SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

 Full stack development using Java EE and Ember.js of enterprise web applications for remote management of company owned mobile devices.

## JUNIOR – INTERMEDIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Full stack development using TCL and Backbone.js of an online casino and sports betting portal for a Canadian casino at playnow.com
- Special emphasis was put into database performance and high concurrency.

### SAP INTERN SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Vancouver, Canada Sept 2009 - Sept 2010 • Java development of installation software for a business intelligence suite (Crystal Reports).

### **EDUCATION**

# SIMON FRASER UNIVERSITY

Burnaby, Canada Sept 2008 - Apr 2012

### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTING SCIENCE

• Concentration in distributed systems.